Who is going to find out?
¿Quién se va a enterar?
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
Australia or to say your
Australia o, mejor dicho, su
country
país,
which is very good at
que es muy bueno para
getting all the black money.
conseguir todo el dinero negro.  a
to Switzerland.
Suiza.
[UNCLEAR] stupid things are done.
[NO CLARO] Se hacen cosas estúpidas.  ¿
What is the need to allow the money to
Cuál es la necesidad de permitir que el dinero
go out of [UNCLEAR] I don't understand
salga de [NO ESTÁ CLARO] No entiendo el
cash money, you see
dinero en efectivo, verás
that only has black market.
que solo tiene mercado negro.
[UNCLEAR] maybe taxation binds
[NO CLARO] tal vez los impuestos vinculan las
military things.
cosas militares.
You tax someone
Se cobran impuestos a alguien
all right, you tax for something sensible, nobody minds
, se cobran por algo sensato, a nadie le importa
but for buying military things and then seeking [UNCLEAR]
excepto por comprar cosas militares y luego buscar [NO CLARO] ¿
What's the use?
De qué sirve?
While your hard-earned money
Mientras el dinero que tanto le costó ganar,
the tax payer is going in the
el contribuyente va a la
see of [UNCLEAR]
sede de [NO CLARO]
[UNCLEAR] Where are you two going?
[NO CLARO] ¿Adónde van ustedes dos?
She is buying all these materials,
Ella está comprando todos estos materiales,
more materials, [UNCLEAR] finished.
más materiales, [NO CLARO] terminado.
Then, its also, you see, a double solver
Entonces, también es un doble solucionador:
also these horrible Argentinians
estos horribles
people who killed their own people
argentinos que mataron a su propia gente
are being punished now.
están siendo castigados ahora.
All these dictators are [UNCLEAR] punished.
Todos estos dictadores son [NO CLARO] castigados.
That's a very good thing.
Eso es algo muy bueno.
They needed some punishment.
Necesitaban algún castigo.  ¿
Why is she the person who is harmed because she was collecting
Por qué ella es la persona que sale perjudicada porque estaba coleccionando?
She started this, and another is America.
Ella empezó esto y otra es América.
[UNCLEAR] be in trouble. [I will see that UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO] estar en problemas.  [Veré que eso NO ESTÁ CLARO]
very soon.
muy pronto.
Russia is in trouble too.
Rusia también está en problemas.
It will work out, you will see that.
Todo saldrá bien, ya lo verás.
You don't realize how [UNCLEAR]
No te das cuenta de cómo [NO CLARO]
She [UNCLEAR] for ten people [UNCLEAR]
Ella [NO CLARO] para diez personas [NO CLARO]
finished.
terminó.
I will get you small plates for biscuits and cheese Mother.
Te conseguiré platos pequeños para galletas y queso, madre.  ¿
May I keep this as prasad?
Puedo mantener esto como prasad?
I think now there will be a revolution.
Creo que ahora habrá una revolución.
in Argentina and
en Argentina y
[Chile ? UNCLEAR]
[Chile ?  NO CLARO]
In Argentina and
En Argentina y
Chile.
Chile.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO] ¿Lo
Did you follow?
seguiste?
She just doesn't follow. What's the matter?
Ella simplemente no me sigue.  ¿Qué pasa?
I said there will be a revolution now.
Dije que habrá una revolución ahora.
I don't know. [UNCLEAR]
No sé.  [NO CLARO]
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
It's too good.
Es demasiado bueno.  Ya
You see
ves,
But no communism. You see the trouble was
pero no hay comunismo.  Verá, el problema era que
these people were going to communism.
esta gente iba al comunismo.
If they had gone for democracy, [UNCLEAR]
Si hubieran optado por la democracia, [NO CLARO]
Because communism is no solution at all.
Porque el comunismo no es ninguna solución.
It's much worse than dictatorship.
Es mucho peor que una dictadura.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
Yogi: The communist not believe in God. Mataji: Not at all.
Yogi: Los comunistas no creen en Dios.  Mataji: En absoluto.
[UNCLEAR] What's the use of having communism?
[NO CLARO] ¿De qué sirve tener comunismo?
Yogi: They are very materialistic even.
Yogi: Son muy materialistas incluso.
Mataji: Very materialistic.
Mataji: Muy materialista.
And this was the mistake of Chile people and Argentina people to ask for communism.
Y ese fue el error del pueblo chileno y del pueblo argentino al pedir el comunismo.  Los
Communist wouldn't even know what has happened.
comunistas ni siquiera sabrían lo que pasó.
Nice to see communism from far.
Es bueno ver el comunismo desde lejos.  ¿
How communism?
Cómo comunismo?
That was a mistake.
Eso fue un error.  Los
Chile people are slo stupid.
chilenos también son estúpidos.
They don't understand what communism is.
No entienden qué es el comunismo.
Russia will just come and sit on their head.
Rusia simplemente vendrá y se sentará sobre sus cabezas.
Whatever happened to Poland see.
Lo que pasó con Polonia, ¿ves?
Czechoslovakia finished, Poland finished.
Terminó Checoslovaquia, terminó Polonia.
It could finish too.
También podría terminar.
Afghanistan tried to [UNCLEAR] something.
Afganistán intentó [NO CLARO] algo.
They are sitting on their heads now.
Ahora están sentados sobre sus cabezas.
Only the Indians are saved.
Sólo los indios se salvan.
Yogi: Now the church.
Yogui: Ahora la iglesia.
Yogi: The Church in Chile, they are very political Mother.
Yogi: La Iglesia en Chile, es Madre muy política.
Mataji: Church? Yogi:Yes.
Mataji: ¿Iglesia?  Yogui: Sí.
[UNCLEAR] What about your Pope?
[NO CLARO] ¿Qué pasa con tu Papa?
[UNCLEAR] a political stunt.
[NO CLARO] un truco político.
He said,"I don't want any war."
Dijo: "No quiero ninguna guerra".
I mean, who wants war?
Quiero decir, ¿quién quiere la guerra?  ¿
What is the need to say, "I don't want any war"? But give some solution.
Cuál es la necesidad de decir: "No quiero ninguna guerra"?  Pero dale alguna solución.  ¿
What is the solution?
Cuál es la solución?
I don't want to be involved, everything is to be done peacefully.
No quiero involucrarme, todo debe hacerse pacíficamente.
For that you don't need a Pope to say that.
Para eso no hace falta que un Papa diga eso.  La
Church is for teaching them Capitalism.
Iglesia está para enseñarles el capitalismo.
Yogi: Catholic ..
Yogui: Católico.. ¿
How they? from the left people..
Cómo ellos?  del pueblo de izquierda.
Yogi: Communist people Mother.
Yogi: Pueblo comunista Madre.
They [help?] the Communist.
Ellos [¿ayudan?] a los comunistas.
The communist people they [killed?]
Los comunistas [¿mataron?]
They killed this and they killed this, that's all.
Mataron esto y mataron esto, eso es todo.
So, they are just the same.
Entonces, son exactamente iguales.  ¿
What was your Mother's [UNCLEAR] Communism?
Cuál era el comunismo [NO CLARO] de tu madre?
That's [UNCLEAR] stupidity.
Eso es estupidez [NO CLARO].
[UNCLEAR believe in communism.
[NO ESTÁ CLARO creer en el comunismo.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
Yogi: In 1970
Yogi: Desde 1970
until 1970, I was [UNCLEAR] this [UNCLEAR]
hasta 1970, yo era [NO CLARO] este [NO CLARO]
I was very active in Politics.
Estuve muy activo en política.
Because my
Porque mi
mother [UNCLEAR]  and myself
madre [NO ESTÁ CLARO] y yo hemos
to do politics since.
hecho política desde entonces.  ¿
So [UNCLEAR]  and myself you were communist?
Entonces [NO ESTÁ CLARO] y yo éramos comunistas?
I was [UNCLEAR]   You worked for communist that time? I was socialist.
Yo estaba [NO CLARO] ¿Trabajaste para los comunistas esa vez?  Yo era socialista.
Yes communist.
Sí comunista.
See, now you see the stupidity of communism is there.
Mira, ahora ves que la estupidez del comunismo está ahí.
Complete.
Completo.
That was the mistake.
Ese fue el error.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
They don't understand God at all.
No entienden a Dios en absoluto.
They are absurd people.
Son gente absurda.
Sahajayoga would have never reached to [UNCLEAR]  were a communist.
Sahajayoga nunca habría llegado a [NO CLARO] si fuera comunista.
Of course, now, you have given up all your political.
Por supuesto, ahora has renunciado a toda tu política.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
He too was.
Él también lo estaba.
I was never
Nunca me gustó
very much into. Mataji: But your brothers and sisters, were [UNCLEAR]  ?
mucho.  Mataji: Pero tus hermanos y hermanas, ¿eran [NO CLAROS]?
He is married.
El está casado.
Wendy is
Wendy es la
Geraldo's sister. Wendy is married with my brother, so the relation is, he is my
hermana de Geraldo.  Wendy está casada con mi hermano, entonces la relación es, él es mi
My brother is married with Geraldo's sister.
hermano. Mi hermano está casado con la hermana de Geraldo.
Mataji: Rodrigo is your brother?
Mataji: ¿Rodrigo es tu hermano?
Mataji: So Rodrigo's wife is Wendy? Yogi: Yes.
Mataji: ¿Entonces la esposa de Rodrigo es Wendy?  Yogui: Sí.
[Yogis and Mataji talk about relations]
[Los yoguis y Mataji hablan sobre las relaciones]
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
All these things should be understood in the light of the spirit.
Todas estas cosas deben entenderse a la luz del espíritu.
It's difficult to understand.
Es difícil de entender.
Without democracy you cannot have realization.
Sin democracia no se puede tener realización.  No
Cannot work out.
puedo funcionar.
I cannot go to any country which is communist.
No puedo ir a ningún país que sea comunista.
And do sahajayoga.
Y haz sahajayoga.
Nor can I go to any country where there is [UNCLEAR]  rule
Tampoco puedo ir a ningún país donde haya reglas [NO CLARAS]
So both are useless. Only democratic countries we can work out.
Así que ambas son inútiles.  Sólo los países democráticos podemos funcionar.
We have thought we have done, you see,
Hemos pensado que lo hemos hecho, verás,
We have gone to France, Portugal, all these people are democratic.
hemos ido a Francia, Portugal, toda esta gente es democrática.
[UNCLEAR]  communism had [UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO] el comunismo tenía [NO CLARO]
This is what it is.
Esto es lo que es.  Son cosas
Very wrong misleading
muy equivocadas y engañosas
things these are.
.
The car fellow was just changing everything
El tipo del auto simplemente estaba cambiando todo lo que
he was cheating.
estaba haciendo trampa.
First he said something, and he changed everything horrible people.
Primero dijo algo y cambió todo, gente horrible.
They are always trying to get your money.
Siempre están tratando de sacar tu dinero.
Spanish, you see, have worse
Los españoles, ya ves, peores
worst are these [UNCLEAR].
peores son estos [NO CLARO].
what you call Italians.
lo que llamas italianos.
They are the worst, terrible.
Son los peores, terribles.  Los
Portuguese are very good people compared to Spanish actually.
portugueses son muy buena gente en comparación con los españoles.
They are very good people, they don't cheat you, they trust you.
Son muy buena gente, no te engañan, confían en ti.
They are very good people.
Son muy buena gente.
We went to
Fuimos al
[UNCLEAR]   place
lugar [NO CLARO]
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
We wanted to buy some marbles
Queríamos comprar algunas canicas
[UNCLEAR]   small small pieces, small of marbles
[NO CLARO] piezas pequeñas, pequeñas de canicas
First, they said [UNCLEAR]
Primero, dijeron [NO CLARO]
[UNCLEAR]  I mean really went on.
[NO CLARO] Quiero decir, realmente continuamos.
All increasing decreasing, ever expanding,
Todo aumenta, disminuye, se expande constantemente,
every sort of thing, you know. I got so fed up.
todo tipo de cosas, ya sabes.  Me harté tanto.
I went to 2 or 3 shops, [UNCLEAR]   these people, horrible.
Fui a 2 o 3 tiendas, [NO CLARO] esta gente, horrible.
Such a waste of time, you see. Then I  just thought
Qué pérdida de tiempo, ya ves.  Entonces pensé que había
I said, "If the Italians" [UNCLEAR]
dicho: "Si los italianos" [NO ESTÁ CLARO]
[UNCLEAR]  she [UNCLEAR] in 5 minutes.
[NO ESTÁ CLARO] ella [NO ESTÁ CLARO] en 5 minutos.  Lo
Got the whole thing very cheap.
conseguí todo muy barato.
Such liars actually, terrible liars.
Mentirosos así, en realidad, mentirosos terribles.
I said this, I said that, unnecessary.
Dije esto, dije aquello, innecesario.  ¿
Where have we parked the car?
Dónde hemos aparcado el coche?
It's convenient.
Es conveniente.
Yogi: I have just received
Yogi: Acabo de recibir
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
from England.
de Inglaterra.
I have just received a call from England.
Acabo de recibir una llamada de Inglaterra.
My wife,
Mi esposa
she has been bleeding
ha estado sangrando
and
y
they don't know what is ...?
no saben que es...?
Mataji: She has been bleeding? Yogi:Yes Mother. Mother: How many months it is?
Mataji: ¿Ha estado sangrando?  Yogui: Sí madre.  Madre: ¿Cuantos meses son?
Yogi:It's been 5 months Mother.
Yogi: Han pasado 5 meses Madre.
Mataji: That's very [UNCLEAR]
Mataji: Eso es muy [POCO CLARO]
is such a common trouble.
es un problema muy común.
Mataji: Many reasons are there for that.
Mataji: Hay muchas razones para ello.
Some of them is that, they use those pills, you see.
Algunos de ellos usan esas pastillas, ya ves.
She maybe alright.
Ella tal vez esté bien.
anyway its common  [UNCLEAR]
de todos modos es un sangrado común [NO CLARO] ¿
Who else? I mean everybody had this trouble.
Quién más?  Quiero decir que todos tuvieron este problema.
She is  [getting too much UNCLEAR]
Ella [se está volviendo demasiado POCO CLARO]
She said it was quite a lot.
Dijo que era bastante.
She said it was quite a lot and
Dijo que era bastante y que
if it carried on tonight, they would take her to hospital.
si continuaba esta noche la llevarían al hospital.
It's an ordinary case.
Es un caso ordinario.
Nothing so extra ordinary.
Nada tan extraordinario.  ¿
Is it too much or less?
Es demasiado o menos?
Yogi: She said it was a lot.
Yogi: Dijo que era mucho.
Mataji: It was a lot?
Mataji: ¿Fue mucho?
Mataji: She talked to you? Yogi: Yes Mother,  she called me.
Mataji: ¿Habló contigo?  Yogi: Sí madre, ella me llamó.
Mataji: Now what did she  [UNCLEAR]  what do you  [UNCLEAR]
Mataji: Ahora, ¿qué hizo ella? [NO CLARO] ¿Qué haces tú? [NO CLARO]
Mataji: You should have told her that
Mataji: Deberías haberle dicho que
you have done sahaja yoga.
has hecho sahaja yoga.
Should have been better.
Debería haber sido mejor.  ¿
Did you say that? Pray to Mother?
Dijiste eso?  ¿Rezarle a la Madre?
Yogi: I did say Mother.
Yogi: Dije Madre.
She was having all these troubles because
Ella estaba teniendo todos estos problemas porque
she doesn't do sahaja yoga.
no practica sahaja yoga.  ¿
How did you get the [UNCLEAR] ?
Cómo obtuviste el [NO CLARO]?
Yogi: When I was, told to call
Yogi: Cuando me dijeron que llamara
urgently to England.
urgentemente a Inglaterra.
Also she might have lifted something, or something like that.
También podría haber levantado algo o algo así.
You see.
Verás.
[UNCLEAR] I can't understand too much.
[NO CLARO] No puedo entender mucho.
Because they start little bit little bit like that you see.
Porque empiezan un poquito así, ya ves.
It's suddenly too much then there must be something she has done.
De repente es demasiado, entonces debe haber algo que ella haya hecho.
with careless [UNCLEAR]
con descuidado [NO CLARO]
Mataji: What about your father?
Mataji: ¿Qué pasa con tu padre?
Yogi: He is in Chile now.
Yogi: Ahora está en Chile.
Yogi: He is [UNCLEAR] with my mother.
Yogi: Él está [NO CLARO] con mi madre.
He is divorced.
El esta divorciado.
He separated from my mother.
Se separó de mi madre.
He live in Chile Mother.
Vive en Chile Madre.
Mataji: With another woman? Yogi:Yes Mother.
Mataji: ¿Con otra mujer?  Yogui: Sí madre.  ¿
You remember him ?
Lo recuerdas?  ¿
He left when you were young or ?
Se fue cuando eras joven o?
Yogi: Actually, my mother left him because
Yogi: En realidad, mi madre lo dejó porque
he was horrible. In 1970
era horrible.  En 1970
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
better for children to separate, And she separate, otherwise we
mejor que los niños se separaran, Y ella se separara, de lo contrario
would be crazy.
estaríamos locos.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
last two years.
últimos dos años.
I write him and I tell him
Le escribo y le digo
sahaja yoga
sahaja yoga
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
Mataji: When did she join politics? Your mother?
Mataji: ¿Cuándo se unió a la política?  ¿Tu madre?
Yogi: My mother was [UNCLEAR] in politics.
Yogi: Mi madre estaba [NO CLARO] en política.
Yogi: My mother is very political, so that's why they are in trouble.
Yogi: Mi madre es muy política, por eso están en problemas.
he doesn't [UNCLEAR] in political.
él no [NO ESTÁ CLARO] en política.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
Mataji: She [UNCLEAR] communist?
Mataji: ¿Es [NO CLARO] comunista?
Yogi: from when my mother was 25.
Yogi: de cuando mi madre tenía 25 años.
something like that.
algo así.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
Mataji: Can you [UNCLEAR]?
Mataji: ¿Puedes [NO CLARO]?
[Visuddhi?] is on this joint,
[NO CLARO]
Put some balm there.
Pon un poco de bálsamo allí.
It's all there.
Está todo ahí.
All side.
Todo lado.  De
This side also.
este lado también.  ¿
Mataji: [UNCLEAR] is going very slow because of [UNCLEAR].
Mataji: [NO CLARO] va muy lento debido a [NO CLARO].
[UNCLEAR] is so much fighting with her.
[NO CLARO] está peleando mucho con ella.
[smoky business?]
[¿negocio lleno de humo?]
very few people are
muy pocas personas lo son.
We have lost so many [UNCLEAR]
Hemos perdido a tantos [NO CLARO]
Mataji: I think something wrong with your Vishuddhi, that's why the voice is not correct.
Mataji: Creo que algo anda mal con tu Vishuddhi, por eso la voz no es correcta.
Something wrong with it.
Algo anda mal con eso.  ¿
You've got this trouble, [UNCLEAR]?
Tienes este problema, [NO CLARO]?
Yogi: Sometime Mother.
Yogui: En algún momento madre.
Mataji: That's the reason.
Mataji: Esa es la razón.
Mataji: That's the reason, that's why you can't hear me
Mataji: Esa es la razón, es por eso que no puedes oírme
and you can't [UNCLEAR]
y no puedes [NO CLARO]
You developed lot's of trouble during that Chile problem.
Tuviste muchos problemas durante ese problema de Chile.
In Chile.
En Chile.
Mataji: You were in jail?
Mataji: ¿Estabas en la cárcel?
Yogi: No, my mother.
Yogui: No, mi madre.
Because it was horrible time.
Porque fue un momento horrible.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
I was so afraid Mother
Tenía mucho miedo Madre
because  when they talked to my mother [UNCLEAR]
porque cuando hablaron con mi madre [NO CLARO]
You see, the knowledge should be such, you should know all your powers.
Verás, el conocimiento debe ser tal, debes conocer todos tus poderes.
You should now what's all is inside you, you should know
Ahora deberían saber qué hay dentro de ustedes, deberían saber
what is wrong with another person, everything
qué le pasa a otra persona, todo lo
that is knowledge that is shuddha vidya.
que es conocimiento, eso es shuddha vidya.
Yogi: [UNCLEAR] the lalita Sahashraranama.
Yogui: [NO CLARO] la lalita Sahashraranama.
It's very difficult book.
Es un libro muy difícil.
Mataji: Now you come to the point. Yogi: I have it.
Mataji: Ahora vienes al grano.  Yogui: Lo tengo.
Mataji: Yes, you read Lalita? Yogi: I bought it in India, yes.
Mataji: Sí, ¿leíste a Lalita?  Yogi: Lo compré en India, sí.
Mataji: That's it, that is what all it is. All right?
Mataji: Eso es todo, eso es todo.  ¿Está bien?
Now put your hand towards me and say, "Mother,
Ahora pon tu mano hacia mí y di: "Madre, ¿
Are you Lalita? Ask the question.
eres Lalita? Haz la pregunta.
Again. Yogi: "Mother, Are you Lalita?" Again. Yogi: "Mother, Are you Lalita?"
Nuevamente. Yogi: "Madre, ¿eres Lalita?" Nuevamente. Yogi: "Madre, ¿eres Lalita?"
Again. Yogi: "Mother, Are you Lalita?"
Nuevamente. Yogi: "Madre  , ¿Eres Lalita?" ¿
All right?
Está bien?
If you have got Lalita Sahashranama, you don't have to do anything.
Si tienes Lalita Sahashranama, no tienes que hacer nada. [
[UNCLEAR] they don't know anything, do they talk? They don't talk of kundalini.
NO CLARO] no saben nada, ¿hablan? No hablan de kundalini.
They don't know anything. I mean they don't even have the knowledge.
No hablan.  No sé nada. Quiero decir, ni siquiera tienen el conocimiento. Deja
Leave alone anything.
en paz cualquier cosa.
Knowledge is also not sufficient, which is not [shuddha UNCLEAR]
El conocimiento tampoco es suficiente, lo cual no es [shuddha POCO CLARO],
which is not pure, shuddha vidya.
lo cual no es puro, shuddha vidya.
Just, put your hand here,
Simplemente, pon tu mano aquí,
put one in Swadisthana here down below.
pon una en  Swadisthana, aquí abajo.
Now, say, "Mother, are you suddha vidya?" little lower.
Ahora di: "Madre, ¿eres suddha vidya?", un poco más abajo.
Yogi: Mother, are you sure? Mataji: No no, this one, this hand, little lower.
Yogi: Madre, ¿estás segura? Mataji: No, no, esta, esta mano, un poco más abajo.
Now ask again, "Mother, are you suddha vidya?"
Ahora pregunta de nuevo: "Madre,  ¿eres suddha vidya?"
"Mother, are you suddha vidya?"
"Madre, ¿eres suddha vidya?" "
Mataji: Again.
Madre, ¿eres suddha vidya?" Mataji: De nuevo. "
Mataji: All right.
Mataji: Muy bien.
Mataji: Everything you belong, all the knowledge you belong, where is
Mataji: Todo lo que perteneces, todo el conocimiento al que perteneces, ¿dónde está
Lalita Chakra? Where is Shri Chakra? What is what?
Lalita Chakra?  ¿Dónde está Shri Chakra?  ¿Que es que?
everything there is. Yogi: Shri Chakra?
todo lo que hay.  Yogui: ¿Sri Chakra?
Mataji: Everything.  Yogi: [UNCLEAR] Mataji: Yeah.
Mataji: Todo.  Yogi: [NO CLARO] Mataji: Sí.
Mataji: Yes, everything, you will know where is hamsha,
Mataji: Sí, todo, sabrás dónde está hamsha, ¿
where is what? Everything you will know. That is knowledge.
dónde está qué?  Todo lo que sabrás.  Eso es conocimiento.  ¿está
all right? Yogi: I like to be
bien?  Yogui: Me gusta ser
initiated in the Shri Chakra.
iniciado en el Shri Chakra.
Mataji: Shri Chakra is already is here.
Mataji: Shri Chakra ya está aquí.  ¿Está
All right?
bien?
It's [UNCLEAR], you are already initiated. Yogi: Can I practice
Es [NO CLARO], ya estás iniciado.  Yogui: ¿Puedo practicar
the bija mantra?
el bija mantra?
Mataji: Bija mantra? Which one you practising?
Mataji: ¿Bija mantra?  ¿Cuál practicas?
Yogi: Hamsha samhala bryam, ananda vairabhayam.
Yogui: Hamsha samhala bryam, ananda vairabhayam.
Mataji: I see. Say before me.
Mataji: Ya veo.  Dilo delante de mí.
Yogi: Hamsha samhala bryam, ananda vairabhayam. Mataji: Again.
Yogui: Hamsha samhala bryam, ananda vairabhayam.  Mataji: Otra vez.
Yogi: Hamsha samhala bryam, ananda vairabhayam.
Yogui: Hamsha samhala bryam, ananda vairabhayam.
Mataji: I am the
Mataji: Yo soy el
mantra vidya.
mantra vidya.  ¿Está
All right?
bien?
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
May God bless you.
Que Dios te bendiga.
He is so good, you see, just ready to have it.
Él es tan bueno, ya ves, simplemente listo para tenerlo.
Work it out.
Resolverlo.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO ESTÁ CLARO]
Only be careful is starting
Solo ten cuidado al comenzar
on Ekadasha, this is, Ekadasha is strong
con Ekadasha, es decir, Ekadasha es fuerte
because of this [UNCLEAR]. Yogi: Thank you.
debido a esto [NO ESTÁ CLARO].  Yogui: Gracias.
Mataji: All right, sit down. You work it out, you come here, every
Mataji: Muy bien, siéntate.  Lo resuelves, vienes aquí, todos
day these boys are going to be here.
los días estos muchachos estarán aquí.
These boys have come all the way from England for you.
Estos muchachos han venido desde Inglaterra para buscarte.
They are going to stay here in this house, you see, this is, they got this house
Se van a quedar aquí en esta casa, verán, esto es, obtuvieron esta casa
so they came and stayed, they couldn't get a house also.
así que vinieron y se quedaron, no pudieron conseguir una casa también.
Now, and you establish sahaja yoga here.
Ahora, estableced sahaja yoga aquí.  ¿Está
All right?
bien?  ¿
Are you all right now?
Estás bien ahora?  ¿Está
All right? So you have to go to work?
bien?  ¿Entonces tienes que ir a trabajar?  Haré
I'll vibrate your sugar.
vibrar tu azúcar.
You are all right now. [much better? UNCLEAR]  All right. [UNCLEAR] come.
Estás bien ahora.  [¿mucho mejor?  NO CLARO] Muy bien.  [NO CLARO] ven.
Let him come. Come. Bring my sindoor.
Que venga.  Venir.  Trae mi sindoor.
Sit down, sit down, sit down.
Siéntate, siéntate, siéntate.  ¿
What is this you are wearing?
Qué es esto que llevas puesto?  ¿
What is it? Yogi: [UNCLEAR]
Qué es?  Yogi: [NO CLARO]
Yogi: It's just a
Yogi: Es solo
its a [UNCLEAR] Mother, a [UNCLEAR].
una madre [NO CLARO], una [NO CLARO].
Mataji: [UNCLEAR], all right?
Mataji: [NO CLARO], ¿de acuerdo?
Mataji: Come forward.
Mataji: Adelante.
Mataji: Eyes closed.
Mataji: Ojos cerrados.
He is all right.
Él está bien.
Good, are you seeing me?
Bien, ¿me estás viendo?
Good, your eyes have improved.
Bien, tus ojos han mejorado.
I am just putting you
Solo te estoy poniendo para que
to protect your eye
protejas tu ojo
[UNCLEAR] for a while.
[NO CLARO] por un tiempo.
All right.
Está bien.  ¿
Better?
Mejor?
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
[UNCLEAR], that is the  best way.
[NO CLARO], esa es la mejor manera.
Nirbichar samadhi, it's called Nirbichara.
Nirbichar samadhi, se llama Nirbichara.
Better not to think.
Mejor no pensar.
He's got all the Ekadasha and all caught up very [UNCLEAR]
Él tiene todo el Ekadasha y todo está muy [NO CLARO]
Mataji: This is the side of [Buddha UNCLEAR] These are Ekadasha.
Mataji: Este es el lado de [Buda NO CLARO] Estos son Ekadasha.
11, one of them is Mahavira.
11, uno de ellos es Mahavira.
[UNCLEAR] is the back agya?
[NO CLARO] ¿Está la espalda agya?
See the Spirit.
Ver el Espíritu.
that's how his eyes are.
así son sus ojos.
This is [UNCLEAR], this is spirit you see.
Esto es [NO CLARO], esto es espíritu, lo que ves.
You seek all the questions.
Buscas todas las preguntas.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
You see there is a, they become you see.
Verás, hay un, se convierten, ¿ves?
Like a prism, they start giving you many many
Como un prisma, empiezan a darte muchas, muchas
images, this that.
imágenes, esto aquello.
This is spirit inside you.
Este es el espíritu dentro de ti.
Yogi: 7 [UNCLEAR]?
Yogui: 7 [NO CLARO]?
5 or 7? Mataji:5.
5 o 7?  Matají:5.
[UNCLEAR]
[NO CLARO]
Mataji: He has read a lot.
Mataji: Ha leído mucho.
What he is doing is [UNCLEAR] isn't it? Yogi: Thank you very much.
Lo que está haciendo es [NO CLARO] ¿no?  Yogui: Muchas gracias.
Mataji: He is realizing it's different
Mataji: Se está dando cuenta de que es diferente.
Yogi: Thank you. Mataji: Yes.
Yogi: Gracias.  Mataji: Sí.
There's a book we have got, I will give you one. All right? You go through that. [UNCLEAR] give him that book.
Hay un libro que tenemos, te daré uno.  ¿Está bien?  Pasas por eso.  [NO CLARO] dale ese libro.
But now, you establish sahaja yoga here, all right?
Pero ahora establecéis sahaja yoga aquí, ¿de acuerdo?  ¿
You have got a house or some work? Have you got a
Tienes una casa o algún trabajo?  ¿Tienes una
room or somewhere to stay? Yogi: I live alone [UNCLEAR] Mataji: Where?
habitación o algún lugar donde quedarte?  Yogi: Vivo solo [NO CLARO] Mataji: ¿Dónde?
Yogi: In here in Madrid.
Yogi: Aquí en Madrid.
I live in a flat by myself. Mataji: Yourself? Yogi: Because I am a brahmachari.
Vivo en un piso solo.  Mataji: ¿Tú mismo?  Yogui: Porque soy un brahmachari.
Mataji: All right, we will see your brahmacharya.
Mataji: Muy bien, veremos a tu brahmacharya.
Mataji: With the Mother
Mataji: Con la Madre,
when you try the brahmacharya, I will put you to trouble.
cuando pruebes el brahmacharya, te pondré en problemas.
Yogi: With [UNCLEAR], who is the [UNCLEAR] ?
Yogi: Con [NO CLARO], ¿quién es el [NO CLARO]?
Mataji: No no, what I am saying
Mataji: No, no, lo que estoy diciendo es que
if you try any
si pruebas cualquier
brahmacharya, you see
brahmacharya, verás que
Mother is a playful thing, she plays, see,
Madre es algo juguetón, juega, ¿
isn't it?
ves?
She is Kalawati.
Ella es Kalawati.
kala, very artistic, kundalini.
kala, muy artístico, kundalini.
She plays art with you.
Ella juega al arte contigo.
And she tries to bring you round, you see.
Y ella trata de convencerte, ¿sabes?
All these ideas of brahmacharya will vanish soon.
Todas estas ideas de brahmacharya desaparecerán pronto.
Yogi: I see, I need to raise my kundalini sooner.
Yogi: Ya veo, necesito elevar mi kundalini lo antes posible.
Mataji: No, no no. You are [UNCLEAR] there on top of your head. Just see.
Mataji: No, no, no.  Estás [NO CLARO] ahí encima de tu cabeza.  Sólo ve.  Ya ha
It's already risen, when are you going to rise? See yourself now.
resucitado, ¿cuándo vas a resucitar?  Mírate a ti mismo ahora.
Feel it in your head, just come on
Siéntelo en tu cabeza, solo vamos. ¿Está
All right? You don't have to rise anymore.
bien?  Ya no tienes que levantarte.
But
Pero
Now, if you get married, then realized souls are to be born, you know many realized souls are to be born.
ahora, si os casáis, entonces nacerán almas realizadas, sabéis que nacerán muchas almas realizadas.  ¿Está
All right?
bien?  Las
Souls are to be born.
almas van a nacer.
Yogi: I have to find my Vairabhi.
Yogi: Tengo que encontrar a mi Vairabhi.
Mataji: Vairab, all right.
Mataji: Vairab, está bien.
You will find in a sahaja yogini, a good one, all right?
Encontrarás en un sahaja yoguini uno bueno, ¿de acuerdo?
Don't worry. Now, you will, you will definitely.
No te preocupes.  Ahora lo harás, definitivamente lo harás.
Now, see
Ahora, mira,
this is the book.
este es el libro.
Yogi: Oh heaven, thank you Mother. Mataji: I will write it down your name.
Yogui: Oh cielo, gracias Madre.  Mataji: Escribiré tu nombre.  ¿
Are you peaceful? Ask him.
Eres pacífico?  Preguntarle.  ¿
Is there still thoughts?
Todavía hay pensamientos?  ¿
He is not thinking?
Él no está pensando?
Ekadasha very strong. It will work out.
Ekadasha muy fuerte.  Funcionará.
You are all right.
Estás bien.
[UNCLEAR] thing would want to take it out.
[NO CLARO] querría sacarlo.
Now, rejoin your self.
Ahora, vuelve a unirte a ti mismo.
Also, practices of sahaja yoga, you have got the book
Además, prácticas de sahaja yoga, tenéis el libro,
you have got the translation.
tenéis la traducción.
Small book. Yogi: You have a small book? Mataji: No no, the small one. Yogi: yes Mother.
Libro pequeño.  Yogi: ¿Tienes un libro pequeño?  Mataji: No no, el pequeño.  Yogui: si madre.
You should make it a point to come to England.
Deberías proponerte venir a Inglaterra.
Yogi: I lived two years in England but Ieft.
Yogi: Viví dos años en Inglaterra pero me fui.
I would like to go back and see. Mataji: Oh yes, you must come.
Me gustaría volver y ver.  Mataji: Oh, sí, debes venir.
Mataji: And let me know first, you take my address from these people.
Mataji: Y déjame saber primero, tomas mi dirección de estas personas.
in the Ashram, we have a very beautiful Ashram.
En el Ashram tenemos un Ashram muy hermoso.
All right, you come along there.
Muy bien, ven allí.
I am there in June July.
Estoy allí en junio julio.
I am there.
Estoy ahí.
So you telephone to them and find out.
Así que llámales por teléfono y averígualo.
And come along. All right? Yogi: Yes Mother.
Y ven.  ¿Está bien?  Yogui: Sí madre.  ¿
How are you?
Cómo estás?
Just see this [UNCLEAR]
Solo mira esto [NO CLARO]
[UNCLEAR]  Om twamewa Sakshyat narakasura mardini Sakshyat.
[NO CLARO] Om twamewa Sakshyat narakasura mardini Sakshyat.
[UNCLEAR] Om Sakshyat Adi kundalini Sakshyat.
[NO CLARO] Om Sakshyat Adi kundalini Sakshyat.
Now, open your eyes.
Ahora, abre los ojos.
Om Sakshyat Maha Vairabha sakshyat. Om Sakshyat Maha Vairabha sakshyat.
Om Sakshyat Maha Vairabha sakshyat.  Om Sakshyat Maha Vairabha sakshyat.
Om Sakshyat Maha Vairabha sakshyat.
Om Sakshyat Maha Vairabha sakshyat.
Om Sakshyaat Aatmaam sakshyaat.
Om Sakshyaat Aatmaam sakshyaat.
Om Sakshyaat Paramaatmam sakshyaat.
Om Sakshyaat Paramaatmam sakshyaat.
Eyes open. Om Sakshyaat ekadasha Rudram sakshyaat. Ekadasha Rudram sakshyaat.
Ojos abiertos.  Om Sakshyaat ekadasha Rudram sakshyaat.  Ekadasha Rudram sakshyaat.
Ekadasha Rudram sakshyaat.
Ekadasha Rudram sakshyaat.
Om Sakshyaat Sahashraha Swamini sakshyaat. Sahashraha Swamini sakshyaat. Sahashraha Swamini sakshyaat.
Om Sakshyaat Sahashraha Swamini sakshyaat.  Sahashraha Swamini sakshyaat.  Sahashraha Swamini sakshyaat.
Sahashraha Swamini sakshyaat. Mokshyadayini sakshyaat.
Sahashraha Swamini sakshyaat.  Mokshyadayini sakshyaat.
Mokshyadayini sakshyaat.
Mokshyadayini sakshyaat.
Nirmalam sakshyaat. Nirmalam sakshyaat. Nirmalam sakshyaat.
Nirmalam sakshyaat.  Nirmalam sakshyaat.  Nirmalam sakshyaat.
Nirmalam sakshyaat. Nirmalam sakshyaat.
Nirmalam sakshyaat.  Nirmalam sakshyaat.
Nirmalam sakshyaat.
Nirmalam sakshyaat.
Now see me.
Ahora mírame.  ¿
Are you seeing better?
Estás viendo mejor?